trafficplanethosting.com 2015-03-14

# Privacy Policy - Traffic Planet Hosting

**What is this Privacy Policy for?**

This privacy policy governs the privacy of trafficplanethosting.com and its users who choose to use it.

This policy sets out the different areas where user privacy is concerned and outlines the obligations & requirements of trafficplanethosting.com users, the website and website owners. Furthermore, the way that trafficplanethosting.com processes, stores and protects user data and information will also be detailed within this policy. 

**The Website:** trafficplanethosting.com

trafficplanethosting.com and its owners take a proactive approach to user privacy and ensure that all reasonably necessary steps are taken to protect the privacy of its users throughout their visiting experience. This website also complies with all European national laws and requirements for user privacy.

**Use of Cookies**

This website uses cookies to improve users' experience while visiting the trafficplanethosting.com. 

Cookies are small files saved to the user's computer hard drive that tracks, saves and stores information about the user's interactions and usage of the website. 

This allows the website, through its server, to provide the users with a tailored experience within trafficplanethosting.com.

Users are advised that if they wish to deny the use and saving of cookies from trafficplanethosting.com on to their computer's hard drive, they should take necessary steps within their web browser's security settings to block all cookies from this website. 

trafficplanethosting.com uses tracking software to monitor its visitors to better understand how they use it. On trafficplanethosting.com, tracking software currently includes that provided by Google Analytics, Statcounter.com, Crazyegg.com and Clicktale.com – all of which use cookies or tracking code in various forms to track visitor usage. These software systems save a cookie to user's computer hard drive in order to track and monitor user engagement and usage of the website but do not store, save or collect personal information. Users can read Google's privacy policy here for further information http://www.google.com/privacy.html.

Other cookies may be stored to usersr computer hard drive by external vendors when trafficplanethosting.com uses referral programs, sponsored links or advertisements. Such cookies are used for conversion and referral tracking and typically expire after 30 days, though some may take longer. However, no personal information is stored, saved or collected. 

**Contact & Communication**

Users contacting trafficplanethosting.com and/or its owners do so at their own discretion and provide any such personal details requested at their own risk. 

Usersr personal information is kept private and stored securely until a time it is no longer required or has no use, as detailed in the [**Data Protection Act 1998**](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Protection_Act_1998). 

While every effort has been made to ensure a safe and secure form to email submission process, we are obliged to advise users that using such form-to-email processes that they do so at their own risk.

trafficplanethosting.com and its owners may also use any information submitted by users to provide such users with further information about the products/services offered by trafficplanethosting.com to assist users in answering any questions or queries that users may have submitted. User's details are never passed on to any third parties.

**External Links**

Although trafficplanethosting.com only looks to include quality, safe and relevant external links, users should always adopt a policy of caution before clicking any external web links mentioned throughout this website.

The owners of trafficplanethosting.com cannot guarantee or verify the contents of any externally linked website despite their best efforts. 

Users should therefore note that they click on external links at their own risk and trafficplanethosting.com and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned.

**Advertisements and Sponsored Links**

trafficplanethosting.com may contain sponsored links and advertisements. 

These will typically be served through our advertising partners and they each have their own privacy policies relating directly to the advertisements they serve.

Clicking on any such advertisements will send users to the advertiser's website through a referral program which may use cookies and will track the number of referrals sent from trafficplanethosting.com. This may include the use of cookies which may in turn be saved on a user's computer hard drive. Users should therefore note that they click on sponsored external links at their own risk and trafficplanethosting.com and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or complications caused by visiting any external links from trafficplanethosting.com.

**Social Media Platforms**

Communication, engagement and actions taken through external social media platforms that trafficplanethosting.com and its owners participate on are custom to the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policies held with each social media platform respectively.

Users are advised to use social media platforms wisely and communicate or engage with them with appropriate due care and caution in regard to their own privacy and personal details. trafficplanethosting.com nor its owners will ever ask for personal or sensitive information through social media platforms and encourage users wishing to discuss sensitive details to contact them through primary communication channels such as by support(at)trafficplanethosting.com.

trafficplanethosting.com may use social sharing buttons which help share web content directly from web pages to the social media platform in question.

Users are advised before using such social sharing buttons that they do so at their own discretion and note that the social media platform may track and save a user's request to share a web page respectively through that user's social media platform account. 

**Shortened Links in Social Media**

trafficplanethosting.com and its owners, through their social media platform accounts, may share web links to relevant web pages. By default, some social media platforms shorten lengthy URLs [web addresses] (this is an example: http://bit.ly/zyVUBo).

Users are advised to take caution and exercise good judgment before clicking any shortened URLs published on social media platforms by trafficplanethosting.com and its owners. 

Despite the best efforts to ensure that only genuine URLs are published, many social media platforms are prone to spam and hacking and therefore trafficplanethosting.com and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or complications caused by users visiting any shortened links.

If any aspect of this Privacy Policy is unclear or you require further information, please contact the Traffic Planet Hosting Support Team via support(at)trafficplanethosting.com

**Resources & Further Information**

  * [Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003](http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/privacy_and_electronic_communications/the_guide.aspx) – The Guide (Easier to understand)
